[
    {
        "question": "$$\\int \\frac{dx}{16+x^2} dx=?$$",
        "options": [
            "$$\\frac{1}{4} \\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac{x}{4}\\right) + C$$",
            "$$\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac{x}{4}\\right) + C$$",
            "$$4 \\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac{x}{4}\\right) + C$$",
            "$$4 \\tan^{-1}(4x) + C$$"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "$$\\frac{1}{4} \\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac{x}{4}\\right) + C$$"
    },
    {
        "question": "$$\\int \\frac{\\sin x \\cos x}{\\sin^4 x + \\cos^4 x} dx=?$$",
        "options": [
            "$$\\frac{1}{2} \\tan^{-1}(\\tan^2 x) + C$$",
            "$$\\sin x + \\cos x + C$$",
            "$$\\frac{1}{2} \\tan^{-1}(\\sin^2 x)$$",
            "কোনটি নয়"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "$$\\frac{1}{2} \\tan^{-1}(\\tan^2 x) + C$$"
    },
    {
        "question": "$$\\int130_{1}^{4}\\;\u200a   ln\u2061x/\\sqrt x dx=? $$",
        "options": [
            "4 ln\u20612\u22128",
            "8 ln\u20612\u22124",
            "2 ln\u20618\u22122",
            "2 ln\u20614\u22128"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "8 ln\u20612\u22124"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\intx^x (1+log\u2061x)dx=?",
        "options": [
            "\ud835\udc65 log\u2061\ud835\udc65+\ud835\udc50",
            "\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc65  log\u2061\ud835\udc65+\ud835\udc50",
            "log\u2061\u3016(\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc65+1)\u3017+\ud835\udc50",
            "\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc65+\ud835\udc50"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc65+\ud835\udc50"
    },
    {
        "question": "x=0  at the point  f(x)=ln\u2061(2x+1) \u098f\u09ac\u0982 \u09a8\u09bf\u099a\u09c7\u09b0 \u0995\u09cb\u09a8 \u09ac\u0995\u09cd\u09b0\u09b0\u09c7\u0996\u09be\u09b0 \u09b8\u09cd\u09aa\u09b0\u09cd\u09b6\u0995\u09c7\u09b0 \u09a2\u09be\u09b2 \u09b8\u09ae\u09be\u09a8 \u09b9\u09ac\u09c7?",
        "options": [
            "f(x)=1+x+2x^2",
            "f(x)=\u22122x\u22122x^2+4x^3",
            "f(x)=x\u22121/2 x^2+1/3 x^3\t",
            "f(x)=2x\u22122x^2+8/3 x^3"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "f(x)=2x\u22122x^2+8/3 x^3"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\int130_{0}^ln\u20612  e^x/(1+e^x ) dx  value is what?",
        "options": [
            "3/\ud835\udc52^2 ",
            "ln\u2061\u30163/2\u3017",
            "ln\u20612",
            "\ud835\udc52^2"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "ln\u2061\u30163/2\u3017"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\int130_{0}^{2}\\;\u200a \\sqrt(4\u2212x^2 ) dx=?",
        "options": [
            "\ud835\udf0b",
            "2\ud835\udf0b",
            "3\ud835\udf0b",
            "4\ud835\udf0b"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "\ud835\udf0b"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\int130_{0}^(\ud835\udf0b/2)\\;\u200a sin^7\u2061xdx=?",
        "options": [
            "8/35",
            "8/15",
            "2/15",
            "16/35"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "16/35"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\int130_{0}^(\ud835\udf0b/2)\\;\u200a  (sin\u2061xdx)/(sin\u2061x+cos\u2061x)=?",
        "options": [
            "\ud835\udf0b/2",
            "\ud835\udf0b",
            "\ud835\udf0b/4",
            "2\ud835\udf0b"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "\ud835\udf0b/4"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\intdy/(3e^5y )  \" value is what?\"",
        "options": [
            "1/(3\ud835\udc52^5\ud835\udc66 )+\ud835\udc50",
            "\u22121/(3\ud835\udc52^5\ud835\udc66 )+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/(15\ud835\udc52^5\ud835\udc66 )+c",
            "\u22121/(15\ud835\udc52^5\ud835\udc66 )+\ud835\udc50"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "\u22121/(15\ud835\udc52^5\ud835\udc66 )+\ud835\udc50"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\intdx/\\sqrt(24+6x\u22129x^2 )=?",
        "options": [
            "1/3 sin^(\u22121)\u2061((3\ud835\udc65+1)/5)+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/3 sin^(\u22121)\u2061((3\ud835\udc65\u22121)/5)+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/3 tan^(\u22121)\u2061((3\ud835\udc65\u22121)/5)+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/3 tan^(\u22121)\u2061((3\ud835\udc65+1)/5)+\ud835\udc50"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1/3 sin^(\u22121)\u2061((3\ud835\udc65\u22121)/5)+\ud835\udc50"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\inte^(\u2212x^3 ) x^2 dx \u098f\u09b0 \u09b8\u09ae\u09be\u0995\u09b2\u09a8  which one?",
        "options": [
            "\u22121/3 \ud835\udc52^(\u2212\ud835\udc65^3 )+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/3 \ud835\udc52^(\u2212\ud835\udc65^3 )+\ud835\udc50",
            "\u22121/(3\ud835\udc52^(\ud835\udc65^3 ) )+\ud835\udc50",
            "\u22121/(3\ud835\udc52^(\u3016\u2212\ud835\udc65\u3017^3 ) )+\ud835\udc50"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "\u22121/3 \ud835\udc52^(\u2212\ud835\udc65^3 )+\ud835\udc50"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\inte^x tan^x\u2061sec^2\u2061e^x dx=?",
        "options": [
            "1/2 (tan\u2061\u3016\ud835\udc52^\ud835\udc65 \u3017 )^2+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/8 (sec\u2061\u3016\ud835\udc52^\ud835\udc65 \u3017 )^2+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/4 (tan\u2061\u3016\ud835\udc52^\ud835\udc65 \u3017 )^2+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/4 (sec\u2061\u3016\ud835\udc52^\ud835\udc65 \u3017 )^2+\ud835\udc50"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1/2 (tan\u2061\u3016\ud835\udc52^\ud835\udc65 \u3017 )^2+\ud835\udc50"
    },
    {
        "question": "x^2+y^2=16  circle area is what?",
        "options": [
            "32\ud835\udf0b",
            "\ud835\udf0b^2 32",
            "4\ud835\udf0b^2",
            "16\ud835\udf0b"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "16\ud835\udf0b"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\intdx/x(x^\ud835\udc5b+1) =?",
        "options": [
            "1/\ud835\udc5b ln\u2061\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc5b/(\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc5b+1)+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/2\ud835\udc5b ln\u20611/(\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc5b+1)+\ud835\udc50",
            "1/\ud835\udc5b  tan^(\u22121)\u2061\u3016(\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc5b+1)+\ud835\udc50\u3017",
            "\u0995\u09cb\u09a8\u09cb\u099f\u09bf\u0987 \u09a8\u09df"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1/\ud835\udc5b ln\u2061\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc5b/(\ud835\udc65^\ud835\udc5b+1)+\ud835\udc50"
    }
]